David J. Liedtka III

Knight-Hennessy Scholar, Naval Officer

Stanford, CA davidliedtka.com dliedtka@gmail.com dliedtka@stanford.edu (609) 915-7139

Computer scientist and experienced computer programmer interested in artificial intelligence, machine learning, and natural language processing. Current member of the inaugural cohort of Knight-Hennessy Scholars at Stanford University. Cryptologic Warfare Officer in the U.S. Navy and 2018 graduate of the United States Naval Academy.

Education

United States Naval Academy

B.S., Computer Science and Information Technology (dual major), May 2018

Academic Order of Merit: 1 / 1062 GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

Overall Order of Merit: 7 / 1062 Graduated with distinction

Military Order of Merit: 17 / 1062

Stanford University

M.S., Computer Science (artificial intelligence concentration), expected June 2020

Awards and Achievements

Knight-Hennessy Scholar

Feb 2018 - Present

 One of 51 selected (out of 3,601 applicants) as a member of the inaugural cohort of Knight-Hennessy Scholars at Stanford University. Currently pursuing an M.S. in Computer Science at Stanford.

Rhodes Scholarship Finalist, District 2

Nov 2017

Trident Scholar

Apr 2017 - May 2018

- One of 13 midshipmen selected for USNA's most prestigious independent research program. Completed a project titled *Prediction of Regional Voting Outcomes Using Heterogeneous Collective Regression*, which applied new Machine Learning strategies to make more reliable election predictions.
- Chief of Naval Operations Distinguished Midshipman Graduate

May 2018

Admiral William S. Sims Memorial Award

May 2018

- For proficiency in Computer Science, as the graduate with the highest grades in classes required to complete the Computer Science major.
- Patriot League Academic Honor Roll

2015-2018

- Four time honoree on the Patriot League Academic Honor Roll. Competed as a javelin thrower on the Naval Academy Men's Track and Field Team.
- Cultural Immersion and Training Trip to Brazil

June 2017

- One of six midshipmen selected to travel to Rio de Janeiro, Natal, Alto Paraíso de Goiás, and Brasília in order to learn about the Brazilian culture and to interface with the Brazilian Navy and the Brazilian Naval Academy, Escola Naval.
- Additionally, a 7x member of the Superintendent's List and the Commandant's List, and a member of Phi Kappa Phi and Upsilon Pi Epsilon.

Work Experience / Leadership Positions

Cryptologic Warfare Officer, U.S. Navy

May 2018 – Present

- Current rank is Ensign. Worked in the Computer Science Department at the Naval Academy, contributing to several programming projects, following graduation. Awaiting next assignment to follow graduate school.
- Intern, National Security Agency

Summer 2016

- Worked in Tailored Access Operations. Assisted developing added functionality to an exploit framework used to facilitate initial access to a target.
- Intern, Maui High Performance Computing

Summer 2017

- Researched expanding Link-Based Classification, an existing Machine Learning strategy, to Heterogeneous Collective Regression, a new strategy enabling predictions over more diverse datasets.
- Company Commander, 22nd Company

May 2017 – Dec 2017

- Served in command of the Naval Academy's 22nd Company, a group of about 150 midshipmen. Was responsible for the organization, well-being, and efficiency of the company day-to-day.
- Vice President, Phi Kappa Phi

May 2017 – May 2018

 Served as vice president of the Naval Academy's chapter of Phi Kappa Phi, the national honor society.

Publications

- Fully Heterogeneous Collective Regression. David J. Liedtka and Luke K.
 McDowell. The 5th IEEE International Conference on Data Science and Advanced Analytics (DSAA2018), October 2018.
- Fully Heterogeneous Collective Regression. David J. Liedtka and Luke K.
 McDowell. 14th Annual Workshop on Mining and Learning with Graphs (MLG2018), August 2018.

Computer Languages

- Python
- Java
- C++
- C
- C#
- F#
- JavaScript

- PHP
- SQL
- MATLAB
- Bash
- Assembly
- HTML
- CSS